{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Montevideo","incorrectAnswers":["Santiago","Buenos Aires","Cali"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Uruguay?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The tail","incorrectAnswers":["The horns","The legs","The claws"],"question":"What body part can geckos snap off and leave behind when in danger?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"The iconic song 'Thriller' was released by which musician?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Deep Purple","Feeder"],"question":"Which British rock band released the album 'A Kind of Magic'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"the mental processes within mental illness or disorders","incorrectAnswers":["life in outer space","a synonym for taxonomy","prehistoric climates"],"question":"What is Psychopathology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The Hula Hoop","incorrectAnswers":["Rubix Cube","Slinky","Pog"],"question":"What toy was released in 1957, creating an instant craze among children?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Steven Spielberg","incorrectAnswers":["Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese","Alfred Hitchcock"],"question":"Which director directed E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Siesta","incorrectAnswers":["Fiesta","Naptime","Asleepta"],"question":"What is the name of the afternoon nap popular in Spain, which derives from a word meaning 'sixth hour'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beach Boys","incorrectAnswers":["Swans","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American rock band released the studio album 'Pet Sounds'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"No Scrubs\" by TLC","incorrectAnswers":["\"Hooked on a Feeling\" by B.J. Thomas","\"Rapper's Delight\" by Sugarhill Gang","\"Fergalicious\" by Fergie and will.i.am."],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"A scrub is a guy that thinks he's fly and is also known as a busta.\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bordeaux ","incorrectAnswers":["Toulouse","Lyon","Champagne"],"question":"Which region of France does claret come from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Aloco","incorrectAnswers":["Borscht","Shawarma","Dholl Puri"],"question":"Which of these dishes is most associated with Côte d'Ivoire?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Gentlemen, you can't fight in here! This is the War Room!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"A census taker once tried to test me. I ate his liver with some fava beans and a nice Chianti.\"","\"What a dump.\"","\"A census taker once tried to test me. I ate his liver with some fava beans and a nice Chianti.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Dr. Strangelove or: How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Bomb'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ernest Rutherford","incorrectAnswers":["Albert Einstein","J. J. Thomson","Niels Bohr"],"question":"Who discovered the structure of the atom?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"It's a Wonderful Life","incorrectAnswers":["WALL·E","Ratatouille","Psycho"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'An angel is sent to help a man by showing him what life would have been like if he had never existed.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Show me the money!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I wish I knew how to quit you.\"","\"What is this? A center for ants? How can we be expected to teach children to learn how to read…if they can’t even fit inside the building?\"","\"You know how to whistle, don't you, Steve? You just put your lips together and blow.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Jerry Maguire'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Centipedes And Millipedes","incorrectAnswers":["Crabs and Lobsters","Slugs and Snails","Scorpions and Spiders"],"question":"Which of these pairs are Myriapods?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Four","incorrectAnswers":["One","Ten","Eight"],"question":"What does the word 'quatro' mean in Portuguese?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"St. Louis Cardinals","incorrectAnswers":["St. Louis Rockets","St. Louis Eathquakes","St. Louis Chiefs"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in St. Louis?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hans Christian Andersen","incorrectAnswers":["Beatrix Potter","Søren Kierkegaard","Oscar Wilde"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Steadfast Tin Soldier'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Paris","incorrectAnswers":["Marseilles","Bordeaux","Monaco"],"question":"What is the capital city of France?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"American Revolutionary War","incorrectAnswers":["American Civil War","World War I","World War II"],"question":"Which of these wars was fought to gain independence from Great Britain?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["France","The USA","Greece"],"question":"In which country was paper money first used?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["Silver","Gold","Platinum"],"question":"In Western cultures, what is the traditional gift for a 20th wedding anniversary?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Gregorian calendar","incorrectAnswers":["The Julian calendar","The Hebrew calendar","The Islamic calendar"],"question":"What is the name of the calendar first used in 1582, in which January is the first month of the year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Chadwick Boseman","incorrectAnswers":["Clark Gregg","Robert Downey Jr.","Benedict Wong"],"question":"Which actor played the role of T'Challa in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Henry V","incorrectAnswers":["James III","Richard II","William I"],"question":"Who was King Of England During The Battle Of Agincourt?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephenie Meyer","incorrectAnswers":["Jack Vance","Brandon Sanderson","Robert A. Heinlein"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Breaking Dawn'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Monoliths discovered generations ago lead mankind on a journey to Jupiter.","incorrectAnswers":["A group of low-level criminals fight to track down a priceless stolen diamond.","A screenwriter develops a relationship with a faded film star determined to make a return.","The stepdaughter of a sadistic army officer escapes into an eerie fantasy world."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie 2001: A Space Odyssey?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Garlic","incorrectAnswers":["Chili","A Crucifix","Silver"],"question":"What Is Worn Around The Neck To Keep Vampires Away?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Osprey","incorrectAnswers":["Peregrine falcon","Golden eagle","Kestrel"],"question":"Which of these birds of prey mainly feeds on fish?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1918","incorrectAnswers":["1920","1914","1931"],"question":"In What Year Did World War I End?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bon Jovi","incorrectAnswers":["Incubus","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which rock band from the United States released the song 'It's My Life'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Sorry!","incorrectAnswers":["Monopoly","Chess","Connect Four"],"question":"What is the name of the classic board game where players must move pieces around a board in an effort to get all their pieces \"home\" first?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Raoul","incorrectAnswers":["Pedro","Mikel","Sergio"],"question":"What's fidel castro's brother's name? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Ukiyo-e","incorrectAnswers":["Impressionism","Mannerism","Surrealism"],"question":"The painting \"The Great Wave off Kanagawa\" by Hokusai is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Black Russian ","incorrectAnswers":["Dark and Stormy","Old Fashioned","Daiquiri"],"question":"Which cocktail consists of Tia Maria, vodka and coke?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Baseball","incorrectAnswers":["Basketball","Football","Ice Hockey"],"question":"Which sport is played by the Minnesota Twins?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Donny Osmond","incorrectAnswers":["David Bowie","Elton John","The Carpenters"],"question":"Who Had A Number One Hit With Puppy Love In 1972?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Cello","incorrectAnswers":["Viola","Double Bass","Harp"],"question":"What is the name of the second-largest member of the violin family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beach Boys","incorrectAnswers":["Swans","The Velvet Underground","Aerosmith"],"question":"Which American rock band released the song 'Good Vibrations'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Lady Gaga","incorrectAnswers":["Hikaru Utada","Drake","Madonna"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter, and actress released the song 'LoveGame'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Russia","incorrectAnswers":["Argentina","Hungary","Spain"],"question":"In which country would you find The Kremlin and Red Square?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Magnetic","incorrectAnswers":["Methanol","Molecule","Mutagen"],"question":"What does the M in MRI stand for?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pacific Ocean","incorrectAnswers":["Indian Ocean","Atlantic Ocean","Mediterranean Sea"],"question":"The Philippines is an archipelago of 7,107 islands in the ________________","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1972","incorrectAnswers":["1954","1960","1966"],"question":"In which year was The Godfather released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["San Marino","Bosnia and Herzegovina","Czech Republic"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Slovenia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hokusai","incorrectAnswers":["‎Pablo Picasso","Vasily Kandinsky","Gustave Courbet"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Great Wave off Kanagawa\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Modern Talking","incorrectAnswers":["Sodom","Rage","Edguy"],"question":"Which German synth pop duo released the song 'You're My Heart, You're My Soul'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Snap out of it!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I drink your milkshake. I drink it up.\"","\"Go ahead, make my day.\"","\"You're gonna need a bigger boat.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Moonstruck'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"ICBM","incorrectAnswers":["ABM","HAMB","BOMB"],"question":"What is the abbreviation for a missile with a range greater than 3,400 miles?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Julia Roberts","incorrectAnswers":["Joan Allen","Juliette Binoche","Ellen Burstyn"],"question":"Who won the 2000 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of Erin Brockovich in Erin Brockovich?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Terry Pratchett","incorrectAnswers":["George R R Martin","Ursula Le Guin","Stephen King"],"question":"Who wrote the \"Discworld\" series?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Piglet","incorrectAnswers":["A Leveret","A Tadpole","A Bunny"],"question":"What is the word for a young hedgehog?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Apple ","incorrectAnswers":["Blackberry","Strawberry","Banana"],"question":"Which fruit is traditionally covered with toffee at a fairground?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Monotype","incorrectAnswers":["Watercolor","Mache","Stenography"],"question":"What is the word given to a unique image printed from a polished plate which has been painted with a design in ink?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Zombies","incorrectAnswers":["The Beatles","The Monkees","The Beach Boys"],"question":"Which group had a 60s hit with the song \"She's not there\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Harry Potter","incorrectAnswers":["Voyages Extraordinaires","Percy Jackson & the Olympians","Twilight"],"question":"In which book series does 'Gilderoy Lockhart' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Portugal","Switzerland","Hungary"],"question":"In which country is the city of Florence?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Night the Lights Went Out in Georgia","incorrectAnswers":["It's Raining Men","Mmm Mmm Mmm Mmm","Achy Breaky Heart"],"question":"What song did Vicki Lawrence have a hit with in 1973?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Bull","incorrectAnswers":["A Macho","A Dog","A Jack"],"question":"A male elephant is known as what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Scarface","incorrectAnswers":["The Night of the Hunter","The Manchurian Candidate","Casablanca"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Tony Montana'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Shawshank Redemption","incorrectAnswers":["Escape from Alcatraz","The Green Mile","The Longest Yard"],"question":"Which prison film, based on a Stephen King tale, starred Tim Robbins and Morgan Freeman?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"1999","incorrectAnswers":["Purple Rain","Kiss","Let's Go Crazy"],"question":"Which Prince hit from 1983 begins with the lyrics, 'I was dreamin' when I wrote this, so sue me if I go too fast'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Austin Powers: International Man of Mystery","incorrectAnswers":["Die Hard","The Adventures of Robin Hood","Pulp Fiction"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Dr. Evil'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Grinch","incorrectAnswers":["Scrooge","Darth Vader","The Wicked Witch of the West"],"question":"Which character's heart was described as being '2 sizes too small' and had reasons for his grumpiness?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Helium","incorrectAnswers":["Nitrogen","Oxygen","Carbon dioxide"],"question":"In modern non-rigid airships, what gas replaced the explosive hydrogen gas used in past airships?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Kippah","incorrectAnswers":["Topi","Taqiyah","Capotain"],"question":"What is the traditional Jewish head covering for men?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Great Fire","incorrectAnswers":["The Bubonic Plague","The Execution of Charles II","The Unification of Great Britain"],"question":"The Monument in the City Of London is a monument to which event?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Peter Sellers","incorrectAnswers":["Daniel Day-Lewis","Marlon Brando","Robert Duvall"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Inspector Jacques Clouseau in The Pink Panther?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Hemlock","incorrectAnswers":["Spruce","Pine","Fir"],"question":"Which plant was Socrates given to drink to carry out his death sentence?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Battle of Trafalgar","incorrectAnswers":["Battle of the Chesapeake","Battle of the Silarius River","Battle of Actium"],"question":"In which battle was Horatio Nelson fatally wounded?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Chickpeas ","incorrectAnswers":["Lentils","Split Yellow Peas","Adzuki"],"question":"What type of pulses are used in humous?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sweden ","incorrectAnswers":["Denmark","Finland","Norway"],"question":"Which country does one associate with 'Lussekatter'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Isaac Newton","incorrectAnswers":["Albert Einstein","Marie Curie","Galileo Galilei"],"question":"Who discovered the law of gravity?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Do It Yourself","incorrectAnswers":["Done It Yet","Do I? Yes.","Down In Yellow"],"question":"What do the letters 'DIY' mean?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Rajasthan","incorrectAnswers":["Madhya Pradesh","Maharashtra","Uttar Pradesh"],"question":"Which is the largest state in India?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Soup pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Stuffed pasta","Tubular pasta","Shaped pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is orzo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mount Ararat","incorrectAnswers":["Mount Erciyes","Mount Uludağ","Mount Tahtalı"],"question":"Which mountain is the highest peak in Turkey and is considered a national symbol?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Green","incorrectAnswers":["Blue","Red","Yellow"],"question":"What is the traditional color associated with St. Patrick's Day?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Beverly Hills Cop","incorrectAnswers":["Top Gun","The Breakfast Club","Ghostbusters"],"question":"What 1980s movie featured the Harold Faltermeyer song 'Axel F.'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"wine","incorrectAnswers":["plant diseases","parasitic worms","male health and disease"],"question":"What is Oenology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sierra Leone","incorrectAnswers":["Syria","Tuvalu","United States of America"],"question":"Freetown is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Catherine Zeta-Jones","incorrectAnswers":["Kathy Bates","Julianne Moore","Queen Latifah"],"question":"Who won the 2002 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Velma Kelly in Chicago?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Whey","incorrectAnswers":["Creatine","Oodle","Lactil"],"question":"What is the name given to the watery part of milk left after making cheese?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Stegosaurus","incorrectAnswers":["Tyrannosaurus Rex","Diplodocus","Ankylosaurus"],"question":"Which dinosaur had a long, spiked tail?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Red Hot Chili Peppers","incorrectAnswers":["The Monkees","Black Flag","Journey"],"question":"Which American rock band released the studio album 'Stadium Arcadium'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Waterloo","incorrectAnswers":["Dancing Queen","Super Trouper","Fernando"],"question":"With What Song Did Abba Win The Eurovision Song Contest In 1974","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Memento","incorrectAnswers":["Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind","The Butterfly Effect","Donnie Darko"],"question":"What is the title of the film in which the protagonist uses tattoos to keep track of his life?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Homer","incorrectAnswers":["Charles Darwin","Vasco da Gama","Mani"],"question":"Which influential poet wrote The Iliad and The Odyssey?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Pear Tree","incorrectAnswers":["Oak Tree","Maple Tree","Birch Tree"],"question":"Which type of tree is known for its fragrant white flowers?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Just a Friend","incorrectAnswers":["Achy Breaky Heart","Round And Round","Whoomp! (There It Is)"],"question":"What song did Biz Markie have a hit with in 1997?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Vodka ","incorrectAnswers":["Whiskey","Gin","Martini"],"question":"A black Russian cocktail is made with one part coffee liqueur and two parts of which spirit?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"An NYPD officer tries to save his wife taken hostage by terrorists during a Christmas party.","incorrectAnswers":["In a post-apocalyptic wasteland, a woman rebels against a tyrannical ruler.","The story of how the scandal of child molestation within the Boston Catholic church was uncovered.","A rat makes an unusual alliance with a young kitchen worker at a famous restaurant."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Die Hard?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Kingston","incorrectAnswers":["Havana","San Juan","Port-au-Prince"],"question":"Which Caribbean capital is located near the foothills of the Blue Mountains?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Lightning","incorrectAnswers":["Waves","Galaxies","Clouds"],"question":"Forked, Sheet, and Ball are types of what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A centrifuge","incorrectAnswers":["A blender","A juicer","A mixer"],"question":"What machine is used to separate denser substances from less dense ones by spinning them around in a container?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Feathers","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Bones","Teeth"],"question":"A robin has nearly 3,000 __________","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The first documented Siamese twins","incorrectAnswers":["The first people to fly across the Atlantic","The discoverers of DNA","The first people to give/receive a liver transplant"],"question":"Who Were Chang And Eng Bunker?","difficulty":"hard"},